# **Zhaoxuan Tan**

Address: Room 206, Pengkang Building, No. 28, West Xianning Road, Xi'an, China

Email: tanzx9@gmail.com, tanzhaoxuan@stu.xjtu.edu.cn,

Homepage: zhaoxuan.info

### **Research Interests**

I am broadly interested in knowledge graphs, social network analysis, natural language processing, and graph mining. My previous research includes Twitter bot detection, knowledge graph reasoning, and graph representation learning, with a special focus on **knowledge base reasoning and its integration with NLP**, and **social network analysis for the common good**.

### **Education**

Xi'an Jiaotong University, Xi'an, Shaanxi, China (member of the C9 league in China) 2019.08 - present B.E. in Computer Science and Technology

GPA: 89.05 (+3)/100, top 6% [transcript]

Thesis Advisor: Prof. Minnan Luo

# Publications (\* indicates equal contribution)

### [1] Contrastive Learning with Graph Context Modeling for Sparse Knowledge Graph Completion.

Zhaoxuan Tan, Zilong Chen, Shangbin Feng, Qingyue Zhang, Qinghua Zheng, Jundong Li, Minnan Luo. arXiv preprint arXiv:2208.07622, 2022.

### [2] TwiBot-22: Towards Graph-Based Twitter Bot Detection.

Shangbin Feng\*, Zhaoxuan Tan\*, Herun Wan\*, Ningnan Wang\*, Zilong Chen\*, Binchi Zhang\*, Qinghua Zheng, Wenqian Zhang, Zhenyu Lei, Shujie Yang, Xinshun Feng, Qingyue Zhang, Hongrui Wang, Yuhan Liu, Yuyang Bai, Heng Wang, Zijian Cai, Yanbo Wang, Lijing Zheng, Zihan Ma, Jundong Li, Minnan Luo. In *Proceedings of the NeurIPS, Datasets and Benchmarks Track, 2022.* 

# [3] PAR: Political Actor Representation Learning with Social Context and Expert Knowledge.

Shangbin Feng, Zhaoxuan Tan, Zilong Chen, Peisheng Yu, Qinghua Zheng, Xiaojun Chang, Minnan Luo.

In Proceedings of Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP), 2022.

### [4] Heterogeneity-aware Twitter Bot Detection with Relational Graph Transformers.

Shangbin Feng, Zhaoxuan Tan, Rui Li, Minnan Luo.

In Proceedings of AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2022. [15% acceptance rate]

# [5] KALM: Knowledge-Aware Integration of Local, Document, and Global Contexts for Long Document Understanding.

Shangbin Feng, Zhaoxuan Tan, Wenqian Zhang, Zhenyu Lei, Yulia Tsvetkov. arXiv preprint arXiv:2210.04105, 2022.

#### [6] AHEAD: A Triple Attention Based Heterogeneous Graph Anomaly Detection Approach.

Shujie Yang, Binchi Zhang, Shangbin Feng, <u>Zhaoxuan Tan</u>, Qinghua Zheng, Ziqi Liu, Minnan Luo. arXiv preprint arXiv:2208.08200, 2022.

# **Honors and Awards**

| Scholarship for Outstanding Students, Third Prize, Xi'an Jiaotong University         | 2022 |
|--|------|
| AAAI Student Scholarship, Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence | 2022 |
| National Second Prize, Contemporary Undergraduate Mathematical Contest in Modeling   | 2021 |
| Scholarship for Outstanding Students, Second Prize, Xi'an Jiaotong University        | 2021 |
| Dean's List, Xi'an Jiaotong University   | 2021 |

| Top Project Runner Up, NUS SoC Summer Workshop                     | 2021                              |
|--|-----------------------------------|
| Honorable Mentioned Prize (top 15%), Mathematical Contest in Mo    | odeling (MCM) 2021                |
| Scholarship for Outstanding Students, Second Prize, Xi'an Jiaotong | University 2020                   |
| First Prize in Shaanxi Province, Contemporary Undergraduate Math   | ematical Contest in Modeling 2020 |
| Dean's List, Xi'an Jiaotong University                             | 2020                              |

# Research Experience

Research Assistant, TsvetShop @ University of Washington

2022.09 - present

- Using machine learning algorithms to answer what percentage of users on Twitter are bots.
- Worked on KALM, a knowledge-aware language model that jointly incorporates external local, document-level, and global context knowledge for long document understanding.

Advisor: Prof. Yulia Tsvetkov

### Virtual Collaboration, CNM @ National University of Singapore

2022.08 - present

- Seeking to understand how the anthropomorphic features of chatbots affect human-chatbot interactions, user engagement, and user experience.
- Crawled data with Twitter API and applied language models to analyze human-chatbot conversations.

Advisor: Prof. Renwen Zhang

Research Assistant, Knowledge Engineering Group (KEG) @ Tsinghua University 2022.04 - 2022.11

- Worked on kgTransformer v2: Unifying Architecture and Pre-training for Knowledge Graph Reasoning, planned for ICML 2023.
- Achieved SOTA; significantly outperforms previous SOTA (NBFNet) by over 14.3% relatively on WN18RR and over 5.7% on NELL-995.
- ullet Won  $4^{
  m th}$  place in the OGB-LSC@NeurIPS 2022 competition WikiKG90Mv2 track (CogDL-kgTransformer). Advisor: Prof. Yuxiao Dong

Research Assistant, Luo lab Undergraduate Division (LUD) @ Xi'an Jiaotong University

- Member: Worked on graph-based Twitter bot detection, knowledge graph representation learning,
   political actor representation learning, and heterogeneous graph anomaly detection.
   2021.08 2022.06
- Authored 1\*NeurIPS'22, 1\*EMNLP'22, 1\*AAAI'22 papers, and 1\*first-author submission to WWW'23.
- **Director**: Promoting undergraduate research by leading a 17-person undergraduate group, and mentoring 9 schoolmates alongside the other senior students. 2022.06 present

Advisor: Prof. Minnan Luo

Summer Workshop, SoC @ National University of Singapore (virtual)

2021.05 - 2021.07

- Attended lectures in AI analytics and IoT and built a Twitter bot detection demo.
- Studied the effect of heterogeneity in social networks.

Advisor: Dr. Lek Hsiang Hui

### **Services**

| Virtual Volunteer, EMNLP                            | 2022 |
|---|------|
| Reviewer for NeurIPS, Datasets and Benchmarks Track | 2022 |
| Reviewer for Learning on Graphs Conference          | 2022 |
| Director of the LUD lab                             | 2022 |
| Web Chair, CSUC21@XJTU                              | 2021 |

### Skills

- Programming Skills: Python, PyTorch, MATLAB, C/C++, bash, HTML/CSS, SQL, LATEX, Git, ssh
- Language Skills: Mandarin (native), English (TOEFL 107: R 29, L 29, S 22, W 27), Cantonese (native)